RAMDHAN AKBAR BAKHAR

Alamat : Jl. Raya SMAN 1 Kramatwatu Serang Banten

Telepon : 081284000413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

LinkedIn : www.linkedin.com/in/RamdhanAB

PROFIL SINGKAT

I am a professional with 5 years of experience in the field of Supply Chain Management Systems Analyst. I am used to analyzing and identifying opportunities, improvements and increasing efficiency in work and collaborating with the Logistics purchasing team and warehouse to achieve performance targets precisely.

I have strong analytical skills and the ability to work well in a team and individually. Apart from that, I have high discipline so I received the best employee award in a multinational company. With a strong background and commitment to good and quality results, I am ready to make a contribution to your company.

PENGALAMAN KERJA

PT. POSCO DX Indonesia - Cilegon Supply Chain Management Analyst System Agustus 2019 - Juli 2024

Responsibility:

- Provide technical support and guidance to manufacturing personnel and other stakeholders to ensure smooth and efficient SCM
- Manage the transportation system for procurement of goods, supplier or carrier transportation and transportation for domestic and export product delivery
- Manage the bidding system for car, train and ship transportation vendors.
- Analyze and evaluate management system progress to identify opportunities for improvement and increased efficiency.
- Work with cross-functional teams to ensure that SCM systems are aligned with business needs and objectives.
- Collaborate with IT and other stakeholders to create new business.
- ensure the SCM flow is integrated with other systems and processes, such as SAP, ERP and MES.

PT. Sumber Alfaria trijaya, Tbk - Serang Marketing Design & Warehouse Januari 2019 - Juli 2019

Responsibility:

- Manage the receipt of goods from suppliers to the warehouse and arrange delivery transportation from the warehouse to the
- Create a stock list of goods in the warehouse
- Create promotional designs and event product layout guides for stores

PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia, Tbk - Serang Asociate Account Officer

July 2017 - September 2018

Responsibility:

- Looking for potential creditors
- Analyzing Creditor Business
- Calculating creditor's business needs
- Make a Balance Sheet and profit loss
- Manage accounts and good relationships with creditors

PENDIDIKAN

Universitas Serang Raya - Serang S1 - Teknik Informatika (2011 - 2015)

KEAHLIAN & BAHASA

- Data Analytics
- Supply Chani Management
- Marketing Administration
- Bahasa Inggris
- Bahasa Korea



DAFTAR RIWAYAT HIDUP

DATA PRIBADI

Nama Lengkap : Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar Tempat, Tanggal Lahir : Bandung, 20 Maret 1991

Jenis Kelamin : Laki-Laki Kewarganegaraan : Indonesia Agama : Islam Status : Menikah

Alamat : Jl. Raya SMAN 1 Kramatwatu No. 3 Rt 07 Rw 04

Kab. Serang

No. Telpon : 081284000413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

PENDIDIKAN FORMAL

1. SD Negeri 2 Serang	: Tahun 1997	- 2003
2. SMP Negeri 47 Bandung	: Tahun 2003	- 2006
3. SMA Negeri 4 Kota Serang	: Tahun 2006	- 2009
4. Universitas Serang Raya	: Tahun 2011	- 2015

SERTIVIKAT DAN PENGHARGAAN

1.	Kursus Komputer [MS OFFICE]	: Tahun 2009
2.	Pelatihan Teknik Operasi Dan Pemeliharaan Jaringan 20 Kv	: Tahun 2010
3.	President Director Award [Best Employee]	: Tahun 2020

RIWAYAT PEKERJAAN

1.	Teknisi di PT. Mahiza Karya Mandir	: Tahun 2011	- 2013
2.	Staf Adm Teknik di PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Tahun 2013	- 2014
3.	Koordinator Teknik di PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Tahun 2014	- 2015
4.	QA (Quality Assurance) di PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Tahun 2015	- 2016
5.	DJS (Dana dan Jasa) di PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Tahun 2016	- 2017
6.	AAO (Asociate Account Officer) di PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Tahun 2017	- 2018
7.	PT. Sumber Alfaria Trijaya Tbk (Marketing Design & Warehouse)	: Tahun 2019	- 2019
8.	PT. POSCO DX Indonesia (Supply Chain Management Analyst System)	: Tahun 2019	- 2024

Demikian riwayat hidup ini saya buat dengan sebenarnya.

Serang, Juli 2024

Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar